Finding Aid for the The Fuson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC), 1965-1967 Board of Directors Minutes
  - Minutes of Board Meeting, 3/67
  - Memo to Board from Lou Silberman, 4/67
  - Invitation to Annual Dinner Meeting of NCLC, 4/67
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Student Non- Violent Movement-1960-1962 General Correspondence
  - Letter to Madison Sarratt, Chair of Mayor's Committee on Human Relations from Nashville Friends Meeting, 3/60
  - Letter to Baptist Student Movement from Lowell Fewster, BSM President, 3/60
  - Letter to Freedom Fighter from NSNVM Central Committee, 1/61
  - Letter to the Community from James Bevel, 2/61
  - Letter to Citizens of Nashville, 2/61
  - Letter from NSNVM Central Committee 1962 Letter to Nashville Community Re: Unfair and Immoral Discrimination and Segregation, 2/61
  - Letter from Diane Nash Bevel to Organizations working for Civil Rights, 4/62
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Student Non-Violent Movement-1728790 Re: 2/60 Sit-Ins
  - List of M. and N. Fuson's Tapes, 2/1/90
  - Memo to Bernard Lafayette and Joan Bahner from N. Fuson Re: Fisk Students arrested in, 2/1/90
  - Sit-ins Handwritten list of students not arrested Fisk Forums Possible Sit-in Participants from Fisk University, 2/60
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Student Non- Violent Movement Voice of the Movement Vol. 1-18, 1961-1963 3/63 Vol. 3, No. 18 Organizations and Community Activities-Tennessee Council on Human Relations (TCHC)-1965 Correspondence and Minutes of Meetings
  - Minutes of Annual Membership Meeting, 1/65
  - Letter to Mayor Beverly Briley from Avon Williams, 2/65
  - Brochure to Join TCHC, 10/65
  - Proposed Budget, 11/65
  - Program of 8th Annual Meeting of TCHC, 11/65
  - Letter to Friend from John E. Hill, 4/66
  - Letter to Member of TCHC from Baxton Bryant, 4/66
  - Letter to Council Member from T. A. Smedley, 6/66
  - Letter Announcing Workshop from Baxton Bryant, 9/66
- Organizations and Community Activities-Tennessee Council on Human Relations (TCHC)-1965-1967 Newsletters and Public Events Notices
  - Newsletter, 1/65
  - Registration for Annual Meeting, 1/65
  - Press Release: "African Students Arrested in Nashville" 3-5/65 Newsletter 3-4/66 Newsletter, 2/65
  - Notice of Workshop: "Where is Nashville in Civil Liberties?", 2/67
  - Report of Workshop, 2/67
- Organizations and Community Activities-Philadelphia Yearly Meetings of the Religious Society of Friends 1958 Proposed Statement on Race Relations
  - Letter to Fusons from James Coan of the Social Order Committee Notes: Don't Forget, 11/61
- Organizations and Community Activities-Poor People's Campaign American Friends Service Committee Written Program of Information on the Poor People's Campaign Newsletter from Quaker Direct Action Corps
  - Newsletter from A Quaker Action Group, 3/68
  - Newsletter from A Quaker Action Group, 4/68
  - Newlsetter: "The Phoenix Wind-Up", 4/68
  - Poor People's Campaign Bulleting: "New Timetable" Map to March Site at Tennessee State Fair Grounds, 4/68
  - Letter to Friend from Wilton E. Hartzler of American Friends Service Committee, 5/68
  - Mass Meeting Announcement Mail Appeal "Poor People's Campaign for Jobs and Income", 5/68
  - Financial Report of Interfaith Poor People's Campaign, 5/68
- Organizations and Community Activities-Committee on Racial Egualitv (CORE) Letter to Civic and Social Minded Persons and Organizations
  - Amended Constitution of the Congress of Racial Equality CORE Action Discipline, 7/58
- Organizations and Community Activities-Tennessee A & I Student Demonstrations-4-6/61
  - Resolutions adopted by American Association of University Professsors, 4/61
  - Letter to Etta Simpson from University Discipline Committee, 6/61
  - Handwritten note to Marian Fuson, 6/61
  - List of People to Help get Signatures for Petition, 6/61
  - Chronology Concerning A & I Student Demonstrations, 6/61
  - Handwritten notes of talk with Carolyn Reid, 6/61
  - Summary of Citiziens Committee on A & I Students Decisions made following Conference with Commissioner of Education Morgan, including Correspondence, 6/61
  - Letters to Faculty and Administration, 6/61
  - Statement of Meeting of State Board of Education, 6/61
  - Minutes of Meetings, 6/61
- Organizations and Community Activities-Tennessee A & I Student Demonstrations-7-8/61
  - N. Fuson's Notes from meeting with Commissioner Morgan, 7/61
  - Petition for Reinstatement of students at Tennessee A & I, 7/61
  - Minutes of Executive Committee, 7/61
  - Letter to Kelly Miller Smith from Avon Williams Re:Suspension of College students participating in Freedom Rides, 7/61
  - Memo from N. Fuson, 8/61
  - Letter from Leo Lillard of Student Non-Violent Movement Articles, Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-1944-1947 1944 Bergstrom, Herbert and Glenn Everett. "The FEPC Faces a Crisis: Philadelphia Strike", 8/61
  - The Forerunner Newsletter, Racial Brotherhood Issue 1944 Petition: Statement on the Race Relations Crisis, 2/44
  - Y-Teen College fro Y.W. Knowledge program 10/11/47 White, Walter. "Why I Remain a Negro," Saturday Review of Literature. Reprint Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-1948-1949, 10/46; Miscellaneous articles: "Guam Crime Laid to 3 Negro GI's," "3 Men Named as Farnsworth Slayers in Guam," "3 Negro GI's Held in Guam Murder, One from Frederick" New York Times 1948 Sprigle, Ray. "In the Land of Jim Crow" Pittsburgh Post Gazette 1948 Whitman, Hazel. "The Condition of Farm Workers in 1948" Report to Board of Directors of National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc
  - "Slave Labor Issue" Workers Defense Bulletin, 1/48
  - Pringle, Henry F. and Katherine "The Color Line in Medicine" Saturday Evening Post.(1/24/48) reprinted by The Committee of 100, 1/48
  - "Statement on Interracial Marriage," Congregational Christian Churches, 6/48
  - Announcement of meeting: "Call to Conference to End Segregation and Discrimination", 1/29/49
  - Poston, Ted. "On Appeal in the Supreme Court," The Survey, 1/49
  - "The Social Order Committees" Philadelphia Yearly Meetings of the Society of Friends, 4/11/49
  - Articles taken from New York Times "South Exhibit Asks Negro Art, Bans Race," and "Admits White Student", 4/11/49
  - Article about Ralph Bunche, "National Affairs" Articles. Pamphlets, Brochures about Human Relations-1950-1954, 6/6/49
  - Address: Bunche, Ralph J. "Free Peoples in a Free Society," The Committee of 10, 1950
  - Whitman, Howard. "Washington-Disgrace to the Nation," Woman's Home Companion, 2/50
  - Dickerson, Mahala Ashley. "Negro Lawyer in the South, Part I" Friends Intelligencer, 11/25/50
  - "Parish Welcomes Negro at Pastor" New York Times, 12/50
  - Foley, Albert. "Black Face Minstrels: 10 Reasons Why They're Not so Funny" Catholic Interracialist 1/3/54 "Enforcing Racial Segregation" Letters to the Times, New York Times, 4/52
  - "Working Together" American Friends Service Committee 1954 Schomburg, Arthur A. What is the Schomburg Collection? Articles. Pamphlets, Brochures about Human Relations-1955 1955 Miscellaneous Articles: "Citizens Council Behind Tchula 'Protest' Meeting," "The Reaction," "Edlers Ask Minister to Resign in Durant," "Angry Citizens Ask White Men to Leave," "Accused Holmes Men Deny 'Red' Charges; Claim They not Listed as Subversing," "Cox, Minter 'Bewildered' at Requests of Citizens," "Memo to Some Holmes Countians" Delta-Democrat Times (9/30/55), 4/54
  - DuBois, Rachel Davis. "Keep the Channels Open" Friends Intelligencer, 5/28/55
  - Cobb, W. Montague. "The Strait Gate," Journal of the National Medical Association. Reprint., 9/55
  - "Cox and Minter Case" People in Mississippi: 2 articles: Miller, William Lee. "Trial by Tape Recorder," Halberstam, David. "A County Divided Against Itself", 12/55
  - Changing Patterns in the New South Table of Contents, 12/55
  - Martin Luther King and the Montgomery Story Comic Book Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-1956-1959 1956 Bulletin: The Fellowship of Reconciliation 1956 Political Advertisement: H.J. Ryan for Congress "To all Voters of Nashville and Davidson County", 12/55
  - Rustin, Bayard. "Report on Montgomery, Alabama" War Resisters League, 3/21/56
  - Nashville Community Relations Conference Invitation, 4/56
  - Huddleston, Trevor. "The Deep South and South Africa," Presbyterian Life, 5/56
  - "The Churches Speak" Crusade for Freedom Panel Discussion, Grade 2 "Free Schools in a Free America"; "What the Churches Have Said on the Supreme Court Decision on Segregation in the South" United Church Women publication, 5/57
  - Miller, Alexander F. "Violence: It Need not Happen" 10/58-9/59 Highlander Report: 27th Annual Report of Highlander Folk School, Monteagle, TN, 1/58
  - "What Does the Lord Require?" Sermon for Race Relations Sunday, prepared for National Council of Churches Articles, Pamphlets, Brochures about Human Relations Maund, Alfred. The Untouchables: The Meaning of Segregation in Hospitals Articles, Pamphlets, Brochures about Human Relations-1960-3760, 2/59
    - (Spring) "Dear Alumni," Fisk News, 1960
    - "Report on Nashville 1960; its Problems and Possiblities", 1960
    - "Sit-ins Unseat Jim Crow," Fisk University Forums, 1960
    - O'Donovan, Patrick. "Negros Revolt Against the 'Vertical Plan'", 3/60
  - King, Martin Luther. "Letter from Birmingham City Jail," Circulated by American Friends Service Committee 3/8/60 Daily News Brief Newsletter, 3/60
  - Highlights from Highlander workshop Articles, Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-3/60-6/60 3/16/60 Blanchard, Dallas, Ed. Prospectus Weekly Newsletter of Vanderbilt Divinity School 4/60 Article: "Picketers Won't Be Sidelined", 3/60
  - Articles in The Southern Patriot, 4/60
  - Westfeldt, Wallace. "Settling a Sit-in," NCRC (2 Copies), 6/60
    - (Summer) Moore, Julia, "From Jubilee Bell Tower" Fisk News, 1960
    - Articles. Pamphlets, Brochures about Human Relations, 1961
    - Mail Order Form: The Commission on Social Action of Reform Judaism, 1961
    - 1960, Notice from NCLC: "Wilson-Quick Uses Violence on Negroes Seeking to be Served"
  - Brochure on the history of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference 1961 News Release: "Jailed Sit-ins Given Solitary," Student Non-Violent Movement, 1/61
  - Gunter, Laurie M. "The Effects of Segregation on Nursing Students" Nursing Outlook, 2/61
  - Information Sheet: "A Call for Help" Operation Freedom, 3/61
  - Brochure: "St. Louis Public Accomodations Policy," St. Louis Council on Human Relations 12/61 NAACP Newsletter Vol. 1, No. 6, 7/61
  - Letter to all Pastors from Operation Open City Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-1961 File 2, 12/61
  - Report on Nashville 1961: Human Relations Inventory by Nashville Community Relations Conference, 4/61
  - Homes and Community Brochure by American Friends Service Committee Community Relations Program, 9/61
    - Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations, 1962
    - Cooke, Alistair. "Negroes Take a Seat.", 1961
    - Zinn, Howard. "Albany: A Study in National Responsibility," Southern Regional Council 1962 Face Sheet on Clyde Kennard's Imprisonment in Mississippi, 1960
  - Report of the City-Wide Committee for Equal Services, Knoxville, TN, 3/62
  - Golden, Harry. "The American Dream."Johns Hopkins Magazine Jobs and Color: Negro Employment in Tennessee State Government. Report of Nashville Community Conference on Employment Opportunity, 4/62
  - Wechsler, James A. "The American Saga," New York Post Articles. Pamphlets, Brochures about Human Relations-2-3, 1963; 7/62
  - Draft Proposal: "A Human Relations Commission for Metropolitan Nahsville", 2/63
  - Report of the Southern Regional Council "Desegregation in Higher Education", 2/63
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. Letter from Birmingham City Jail, distributed by American Friends Service Committee Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-5-12, 1963; 4/63
  - NCRC Workshop: Enrollment of Negro Pupils in Desegregated Schools by Year, 5/63
  - Report: "Six Years of Public School Desegregation in Nashville and Davidson County," NCRC, 5/63
  - Stalvey, Lois Mark. "We Moved to an Integrated Neighborhood" Reprint form The Sunday Bulletin Magazine, 5/63
  - Analysis: "President Kennedy's Civil Rights Bill," Southern Regional Council, Inc., 6/63
  - Rustin, Bayard. "The Meaning of Birmingham", 6/63
  - Brochure: "Time is Now to March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom", 8/63
  - Merton, Thomas. "The Black Revolution: Letters to a White Liberal" Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations, 1964-1965; 12/63
    - Spock, Benjamin. "Children and Discrimination", 1964
  - Gunter, Laurie M. "The Effects of Segregation on Nursing Students" Reprint from Nursing Outlook. Vol. 9. 1964 Zoerhiede, Jack D. "But What Will the Neighbors Think?" Forum Series 3 On Controversial Public Issues, 2/64
  - Nashville Community Relations Council President's Report: Oct. 19-63-May, 1965 Articles, Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations, 1966; 5/65
  - "March and Meaning of Black Power" Presbyterian Life, 8/66
  - Report on Mississippi Newsletter of Fellowship of Southern Churchmen, Black Mountain, NC Articles, Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations, 1967; 11/66
  - 6th National Conference of Friends on Race Relations: 3 Essays, Black Mountain, NC, 7/67
  - Bagdikian, Ben H. "The Black Immigrants" Saturday Evening Post Reprint Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations-1968 1968 St. Laurent, Philip "Cinque and the Amistad Mutiny" The Negro in World History 1968 Flyer: "Genocide" Black Panther Party 1968 Newsletter from Refugees of Resurrection City 1968 Brochure: "A Co-op is Born" Rural Advancement Fund 1/15/68 Feinberg, Lawrence "Boyd Charges 'Politics' on Freeways" Washington Post, 7/15/67
  - "Road in Nashville is Still Opposed" New York Times Articles. Pamphlets. Brochures about Human Relations, 3/1968-1969; 3/17/68
  - Dilts, James D. "Highway Robbery: Can We Afford It?", 3/68
  - MacKenzie, John "Nashville Negroes' Plea Halts Interstate 40 Link" Washington Post, 3/68
  - "Hosea Williams, Former Chemist, Speaks Out" C&EN, 6/17/68
  - "Scientist Bakes Bread for Poor" Science World, 7/16/68
  - Mess, Dyer. Letter to the Editor The Tennessean, 9/13/68
  - "News and Views" Metro. Public Schools, 10/68
  - Dillett, Eric S. "Heaven Now or Heaven When?" The Messenger (Quote by James Bevel highlighted), 11-12/68
  - "NAACP Assails Black Militants" Reprint from New York Times, 11/22/68
  - Announcement: "Nashville Perspective" Channel 2 TV, 12/68
  - "But I Read His Book", play Pre-College Players Re: Autobiography of Malcolm X Articles. Pamphlets., 7/27/69
    - Brochures about Human Relations, 1986-1990
    - Browning, Al. Book Review of On The Run "The Story of an 18-year Flight from FBI Pursuit" Coalition for Freedom of Parker and Allen, 1986
    - Boycott Notice of Shell Products "Stop Apartheid in South Africa; Protect Jobs in U.S.A." Brochure: Join African-American Cultural Alliance with Membership Application Press Release: Davidson County/Nashville Coalition "Fight for Justice Continues", 1987
    - "The Church: A Catalyst for Change in the 1990s "NAACP Invitation and Program for Registration Album Program 1961 6-page Written Program to Record Album "We Shall Overcome," Songs of the "Freedom Riders" and the "Sit-ins", Folkways LP # 5591 Bibliography Walton, Frankie S. African Literature in English Fisk University Essays, 2/90
    - Fuson, Nelson, "It Happened in 1961", 1961
    - Bevel, James, "A Movement to End Mass Murder", 1968
    - Jones, Lonenzo, "Community Power, Racism and the Church" Chicago Metropolitan Assurance Co., 1968
    - Shannon, Elaine, "Women in Politics" Slides Nelson Fuson Slide Duplication Order List, Kelly Miller Smith Collection Poetry, 1971
  - Lester, Julius B. "The Death of Justice in Nashville" 2/27/60 Lester, Julius B. "A Burial in Nashville", 2/27/60
  - Ayers, Dane. "The Land of Th/", 3/2/60
  - Chan, L., January 4, 1963; 1/4/63